Tonight we'll talk about the famous, nightly patrols
of the Ameer Ul Mo'mineen(أمير المؤمنين) Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه.
These are some of the most amazing stories of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب).
The Khalifah(خليفه) going around at night on patrols,
to make sure that his Ummah(امة) is fine and well,
to make sure that they are happy, to make sure that they are content.
And he would take along with him people like Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf رضى الله عنه.
He would take with him, his servant Salim(سالم),
he would take with him his servant Yarfah(يرفه).
He had different people accompany him on these journeys.
One night Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه, saw some guests in the Masjid(مسجد).
These were travelers
and the travelers would sometimes stay at Al-Masjid-Al-Nabwi(ألمسجد ألنبوي) they would sleep on Al-Musallah(مصله).
The Masjid(مسجد) was open there's no lock pad.
What are you going to steal from "Masjid-Al-Nabwi(مسجد ألنبوي)"
no speakers, no microphones, no rugs, so it's open.
These travelers Abiree Sabeel(عا برى سبيل) would spend their night in the Musallah(مصله).
Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه told Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن إبن عوف),
would you like to join me, so we could guard them this evening.
Now, they have belongings, so Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) wanted to guard them.
And what can you say about such a thing?
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) guarding these travelers.
You can say it's humbleness, you can say it's a sense of responsibility,
you can say it's love for Muslims, you call it whatever you want.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) is telling another man
who was among the10 who were given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة)
You know Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) and Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن إبن عوف) and their likes,
they've already been given the Bushra Bil-Jannah(بشرا بالجنة).
They are among the 10 who are given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة),
so why not just sit at home.
Why do you have to go through all of this hassle and difficulty,
you already have that badge of honor.
Just do your Salah(صلاة) do your Ibadaat(عبادات) and that's enough,
you're Khalifah(خليفه) and you're guarding and you're spending the hours of the night
these people are sleeping and you're guarding them.
Abdur Rahman bin Auf (عبدالرحمن إبن عوف) said: Yes! Definitely.
So, Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه, he hears a child crying, an infant was crying.
He is crying for some time, so Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) goes to the mother and says,
اِتَّقِى اللهَ وَ اَحْسَنِ اِلَى هَذِا اصَّبِيْحََ
Fear Allah and take care of your child and then he leaves.
The child is carry on crying, he is crying again, He is crying again.
Towards the end of the night, he goes to her and say, what kind of mother are you?
You are an evil mother, your child has been crying since the beginning of the night.
She said: I'm trying to wean him, but he doesn't want to eat the food.
This child still wants to breastfeed
and his mother is trying to convince him to eat, rather than breastfeed.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Why are you trying to wean him, how old is he?
She said: He's a few months old.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said;
الله اتقى,
Why are you trying to wean him then?
Because the complete period of breastfeeding is how long! Two years,
so he said: Why are you trying to wean him.?
She said: "Because Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) does not start paying them, until they are weaned."
Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) does not give the handouts
except when the child reaches Al-Fitaar(ألفطار).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Woe to you, son of Al-Khattab(الخطاب),
What have you done?
And he then in Salat-Ul-Fajar(صلاة الفجر) he was so taken back by what happened
people could not recognize his Qira'ah(قراءة) because of his crying,
he was weeping so bad they couldn’t recognize his recitation.
And then he immediately after Salat-Ul-Fajar(صلاة الفجر) issues an order, a government order
to the mothers around the Muslim world, he sent this message all over, he said;
Don't wean your children too early, because from now on,
you will receive a handout the day your child is born.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: How many children have I killed?
يا عمر اِتَّقِى اللهَ كَمْ قَتَلْتَ مِنْ اَطْفَالِ الْمُسْلِمِيْنَ
How many children have been killed because of you?
What is Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) saying, who did he killed?
Which children did he kill?
This is a favor that he's doing to the people, he's giving them these handouts.
But he was so emotional because of what he saw,
and he was so upset with the law that state that they should be given this money at the age of two.
He considered that he has harmed the Muslim infants
because their mothers are trying to wean them sooner to get the handouts.
Can you think about such a government you don't pay any taxes
and you still receive handouts from the government.
Ya'ani(يعني) now governments are ripping their people off, taking 30% in taxes or more
and they give you nothing.
Supposedly they take this money to offer you services.
Where does all of that money go?
So much money, Where does it go?
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab( عمر ابن الخطاب), first of all, in the Islamic Khilafah(خِلَافَه),
there was nothing called the Zariba(ضريبة) no taxes at all.
They didn't know the concept of taxes.
This concept of Al-Makoos(المكوس), was something that existed
among the Romans and the Persians.
In Khilafah(خِلَافَه) Al-Islamia no Al-Makoos(المكوس).
All what would be taken from you is Zakat(زكواة) if you are capable of giving it
and Ushur(أشور), this is something that was started by Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) and that's like customs
for businessmen who are coming from outside Al-Khilafah(خِلَافَه), they would pay customs,
and we'll talk about that later on.
But the government gives you money
and the moment your child is born you're gonna start receiving those handouts.
During one of his patrols, he passes by this house and you know in those days
the house didn't have a front yard in the backyard, and a huge garden and soundproof walls,
these were very modest buildings, mud bricks and
the house is basically composed of a few rooms and that's it, not very high.
The house of Rasool Allah ﷺ one could touch the ceiling with your hand as Al-Hasan Al-Basri(الحسن البصرى) said.
So, you could hear what's happening inside these houses.
So Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) is walking and he hears a woman and this was very late at night.
This woman was reciting lines of poetry.
تَطَاوَلَ هَذَالَّيْلَ تَسْرِيْ كَوَاكِبْه
وَأَرَّقَنِيْ أَلَّا ضَجِيْحٌ أُلَاعِبُه
The lines go on and in the end , she says,
وَلَكِنَنِيْ أَخْشَى رَقِيْبًأ مُوْكَلًا بِأَنْفُسِنَا لَا يَفْتُرْ اَلدَّهَرْ كَاتِبُه
Basically, this woman was a wife of one of the Mujahideen(مجاهدين) Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله)
her husband was away for a very long time and she was feeling very lonely.
She has no children, she staying at home alone.
So, she was reciting these lines of poetry.
The first line, what it means is,
this night is very, very long, and I have no companion to be with me.
And then she goes on to say that if it wasn't for Allahعَزّوجَلّ,
I would have been with another man,
so basically, she's saying, if it wasn't for Allah, I would have committed Haram(حرام).
And then she said, but because I fear Allahعَزّوجَلّ
and because there's an eye that is watching me all the time.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has appointed two angels to you, one on the right and one on the left.
She said: If it wasn't for that I would have, had the companion with me now.
Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه  said;
"يرحمك الله"
May Allahعَزّوجَلّ have mercy on you.
He wasn't speaking to her he was making the Dua(دُعَا) for her
and then he goes to his daughter Hafsah(حفصه), Umm Ul-Mo'mineen(أم المؤمنين),
and he knocks and Hafsah(حفصه) said: Oh my father,
Why did you come in this late hour, it must be something very urgent.
So, he comes in and he says: For how long can a woman wait for her husband?
How long can she stay alone?
How long will her patience last?
So Hafsah(حفصه) said: One month, two months, three months,
and then after four months her patience runs out.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) immediately issues his orders
that no Muslim soldier should stay away from his wife more than four months.
So, the rotation is four months
you know, even today with the fast modes of transportation,
they don't do four months services, six months a year.
But Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: If that's how long she can wait.
We don't want our sisters to wait longer than that,
if four months is the limit then they should come back after four months.
But there was a problem, many of those soldiers didn't want to come back.
You know, now soldiers are crying, we want to go back to mom and dad.
I want to go back to my girlfriend.
They are weeping they are crying, you see them on TV, they're crying all the time.
But these who were Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله) some of them didn't want to go back.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) had to force them, he sent some orders.
He said: You either go back or I'm going to give you an exemption
but you have to give Nafaqa(نفقه) to your wife, sufficient money
you have to provide her with sufficient money, so that she wouldn't be in any need,
otherwise you divorce.
Otherwise you divorce.
So, you see that these are teachings that show the care that Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) had for the Muslim family.
How eager he was to make sure that men are happy, women are happy, children are happy.
So, four months was the maximum time
but what happened was, in the time of Umar(عُمَر) because now the land that was conquered was expanding
and it was getting further away from Makkah and Madina.
They were starting to establish towns up north and these were military towns
like Al-Basra(ألبصرة), Al-Kufa(الكوفه), Al-Mosul(الموصل), Al-Fustat(ألفستات), Al-Jeza(ألجيزة).
All of  these were towns that were founded my Muslims.
Baghdad(بغداد) was later on founded by Al-Abbasieen(ألعباسيين).
So, you can see that the most important towns in Iraq were actually founded in the time of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب)
Al-Kufa(الكوفه), Al-Basra(ألبصرة), Al-Mosul(الموصل), these are some of the most famous towns in Iraq.
These were initially military towns.
To make it easy on the soldiers, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), he has sent orders to his commanders
to build new towns, so that the Muslims can bring their families in, and they set base there.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) these towns became, so important and so vibrant
that the weight of the Muslim world was actually in those towns
and they became more important commercially and politically, then Makkah Madina.
Obviously Makkah and Madina retain their religious importance
but politically and commercially these other towns picked up.
So, you see that in the time of Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب)
he actually moved the capital of Khilafah(خِلَافَه) from Al-Madina to Al-Kufa(ألكوفه).
They were becoming the center of the Muslim world
and then Damascus, and Jerusalem
and Al-Fustat(ألفستات) which grew later to become a Cairo.
But it was because of Al-Ghazoo(ألغزؤ) because of these military expeditions
that these towns were founded and that's what gave them prominence and importance.
So, now they were moving with their families and going up north to these lands of Ribat(رباط).
So, you can see that how the Ghazoo(غزؤ) was really the central theme with the Khulafah رضي الله عنهم
and you would find that everything revolves around it even commerce, business, building towns everything.
In another occasion, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) heard this woman
also apparently a wife of one of the soldiers,
who was absent it was one line poetry. She said:
هَلْ مِنْ سَبِيْلٍ إِلَى خَمْرٍ فَأَشْرَبُهَا
هَلْ مِنْ سَبِيْلٍ إِلَى نَصَرْ بِنْ حَجَّاجِ
Is there any way for me to get hold of a cup of wine to drink,
and is there any way of me to get in touch with Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) did not like these words.
So, next day in the morning he asks for Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج).
Who is this man Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج)?
So they brought him in and it turns out that Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج) was a young man in Madina
and he was a very handsome young man,
and this woman was asking for wine and asking for Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج).
Now Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج) had some fancy hair.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) said: Shave his head.
They shaved his head, apparently didn't really change him much he even became more handsome.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Put Imamah(إمامة) on,
he became more handsome.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Exiled him out of Madina! Exiled him out of Madina.
You might be wondering, it's not the fault of Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج) why send him out of Madina.?
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was very strict in his commands,
he said get him out of Madina and I don't want him here causing me problems.
Women singing songs about Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج), get him out.
So, they sent them to Al-Basra(ألبصرة).
The reason, why he sent him to Al-Basra(ألبصرة), you might say well he's going to cause Fitnah(فِتْنَه) in Al-Basra(ألبصرة).
The reason why he sent him to Al-Basra(ألبصرة) is because Al-Basra(ألبصرة) is a military town.
He is going to be around soldiers.
However, in Madina, it's peaceful, Madina wasn't in a state of war,
During the time of Umar(عمر), Uthman(عثمان), it was peaceful.
and in that environment Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) did not want to have any Fitnah(فِتْنَه) going on.
So, he sends him to this military town rather than have him, fixing the style of his hair in Madina,
have him go up north and fight.
So, he sends him to Al-Basra(ألبصرة) when the woman heard about that
she was very afraid that Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) might hold her accountable for what she said so.
So, she sent him some lines of poetry saying that,
I didn't really mean that literally, it was figurative speech,
and I have Taqwa(تقوى) of Allahعَزّوجَلّ and I fear Allahعَزّوجَلّ
and I'm not going to get involved in any of that Haram(حرام).
Now, this was just poetry that I was reciting.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Al-hamdolillah(ألحمدلله),
that Allahعَزّوجَلّ has tamed your desires with Taqwa(تقوى) of Allah.
Al-hamdolilllah(ألحمدلله) that Allah has tamed the desires with Taqwa(تقوى).
People have these desires men and women
but the piety the righteousness in your heart tames those desires.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was happy when he heard that.
Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج) sent him a letter saying that he wants to come back to Madina.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Not when I'm alive,
not as long as I'm alive, you're not coming into Madina
and he only came back after Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) passed away.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) again he wasn't sentimental
he wasn't emotional he was very strict when it came to the rules,
he wanted to make sure that the benefit of the whole is preserved
maybe Nasr Bin Hajjaj(نصر بن حجاج) is not at fault, this woman he accepted her explanation,
however Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) does not want to have Fitnah(فِتْنَه) around.
During another night excursion of Ameer Ul Mo'mineen رضي الله عنه
keep in mind that he was the greatest king of his time, greatest leader of his time
we shouldn't say King because he wouldn't approve of that title for himself.
Even though, he had a greater status than the kings of the world.
He was with his servant Yarfaa(يرفع) or Salim(سالم), one of them and
he saw in the distance one woman with her children and she had a camp fire.
So, this is a woman alone with her children.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) sees that fire he wants to check it out, he goes there
and when it gets close to the fire and he sees who was around the fire, it was very cold night.
He said;
"ألسلام عليكم، يا اهل الضوء"
Peace be upon you. People of the light.
She responded, she said: Alaikum-Us-Salaam(عليكم السلام),
He said: Adinoo(أأدنو), Can I come near?
She said: You come near for good, otherwise stay away.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), he approached her
and she was surrounded with her little ones and they were crying.
He said: "What's the problem?"
She said: "We are here because of the cold weather and hunger."
They were traveling and they couldn't go any further.
They were so hungry and tired, they set camp in that area.
And the children were very hungry.
So, they were crying constantly.
And Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: So what is this?
She said: This is water that is boiling, I'm trying to keep the kids preoccupied with it."
What she did was,
she was boiling rocks in water, rocks, stones,
she was dropped them in that port and she was boiling it.
So, that she could tell the kids that food is coming, until they become tired and sleep.
She just wants them to get off crying because they were crying constantly.
So, she said, All right. Don't worry. Food is coming.
And she's boiling for them rocks with the hope that eventually they'll get tired and fall asleep.
What did she say?
She said: We are cold and we are so hungry
and Allahعَزّوجَلّ will be the judge between us and Umar(عُمَر).
She said: "Allah will be the judge between us and Umar(عُمَر)."
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), She doesn't know she's speaking to Umar(عُمَر).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: May Allah have mercy on you
and how does Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) know your condition?"
She said: What do you mean, how does he know our condition.?
يَتَوَلَّى اَمْرَنَا ثُمَّ يَتْرُكُنَا
"How can he assume responsibility over our affairs and then neglect us?"
He is our leader, he is responsible for our affairs, so how can he neglect us, he should know.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), he immediately stood up and he went with his servant,
his servant said; We were running, Aslam(أسلم) said: And we were just running,
he said; We went to the storage, where they used to store the flour,
so we grabbed a sack of flour and some animal shortening, fat
and he told his servant carry it on my back, carry it over my shoulders,
Aslam(أسلم) said; "Ameer Ul Momineen(أميرالمؤمنين) I'm going to carry it for you.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said;
وَيْحَكْ أَأَنْتَ تَحْمِلُ أَنِّيْ وِزْرِيْ يَوْمَ الْقِيَامَةْ
Woe to you, are you gonna carry for me my sins on the Day of Judgment,
carry it on my back, so he puts it on the back of Ameer Ul Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين).
And Ameer ul Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) goes to that woman and he's cooking for her.
Ameer Ul Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) is cooking for this women.
He didn't give it to her and tell her you cook, he was cooking.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) the servant Aslam(أسلم) said;
I saw Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) bending under the pot to blow into the fire,
to ignite it and I was seeing smoke going through his beard.
Imagine the Ameer Ul Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) going under and blowing
the fire and all of the smoke is coming in his face and going through his beard,
until he cooked the food and then he served it himself to the children.
And then he went a side, so his servant came to him and said: Do you have anything else to do.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) did not respond back.
Aslam(أسلم) said: We remained there
until the kids were knocked out, that's it they all fell asleep.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said; I didn't want to leave until,
I made sure that they're all asleep and happy, and then they went back.
Before he left, this woman told Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
أَنْتَ  اَحَقّ بِهَذَا الْأَمَرْ مِنْ عمر بن خطاب
She said: "You deserve to be the Khalifah(خليفه) more than Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب)"
you should be the Khalifah(خليفه), not him.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told her: Don't say but good.
He doesn’t want to make Gheebah(غيبة) about the Khalifah(خليفه).
He said: Don’t speak except good, don’t say anything but good.
And if you happen to visit the Khalifah(خليفه), one day you will find me there,
you'll find me there and he left.
He didn't tell her that I'm Ameer Ul Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين), he just left.
She was very happy and she was making Dua(دُعَا) for him,
she doesn't know that she's making Dua(دُعَا) for Ameer ul Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب),
whom she was complaining about.
Now, how would Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) know the condition of everyone
and how can you hold Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) accountable for every child that is hungry when he's doing his best.
But Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), the Muslims in those days were used to being, so pampered by the Khulafa(خلفاء),
that it was something that they expected, at least this woman did.
When in reality it's not Umar(عُمَر) who's responsible for the fate of every single person
when he's doing his best to help them and serve them.
لَا يُكَلِّفُ اللَّهُ نَفْسًا إِلَّا وُسْعَهَا
Allahعَزّوجَلّ does not overburden a soul, with something that he cannot carry.
During one of his patrols he saw a wool tent,
it wasn't there before this the first time he saw the tent
so he said: Let's go and check that tent out.
So he goes there and he finds a man sitting out of the tent
and there was a woman in the tent and she was moaning in pain.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) asked the man, he said: What's going on.?
The man said: May Allah reward you, carry on with your business,
he doesn't know that it's Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: I insist on you to tell me what is happening.
He said: This woman, My wife is giving birth.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Is there anyone with her?
He said: No! She's alone.
So, this poor woman was delivering and they were on a journey, they were traveling,
so they had to stop there and they set their tent,
they knew nobody in Madina, they had no one to help them.
So, the man was just sitting outside and his wife was delivering.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) immediately left and he went back home.
He went to his wife, Umm Kalsoom Bint Ali Ibn Abi Talib( ام كلثوم بنت علي ابن ابي طالب), he told her.
هَلَّكِيْ فِيْ خَيْرٍسَاقَهَ اللهُ إِلَيْكِيْ
Do you want to accept some good that Allahعَزّوجَلّ has sent to you.
Do you want to accept some rewards that Allah has sent you?
She said: Yes! If that pleases you.
He said: Come with me.
There's a woman who's delivering and he carries with him,
some flour and also some fat, animal shortening.
They used to cook the flour in water and then they would add to it animal fat
and they would mix it together.
So, they went there Umm Kalsoom(ام كلثوم) went inside the tent to help this woman
and Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) sat outside, and he told the man
set a fire for me, make a fire.
So, the man made a fire and then Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) started cooking.
And while he was cooking, his wife calls him from inside the tent and said,
Ya Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(يا اميرالمومنين) tell your friend, congratulate, your friend,
Allahعَزّوجَلّ has blessed him with a baby boy.
Now, the man was obviously very happy to hear the news.
But there was something that was quite terrifying to him.
He heard this woman saying, Ya Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(يا اميرالمومنين).
So, he started walking away from Umar(عُمَر), whom I dealing with.
I can't believe it! This is the Khalifah(خليفه).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told him, don't be afraid.
Come! Come back! Come here.
Help me out! Take this pot.
And you have your dinner and take it to your wife.
So, the man put the pot next to the entrance of the tent.
So, Umm Kalsoom(ام كلثوم) took it.
And she was the one feeding the woman who just delivered and then they left.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told him, tomorrow morning, you come to me
and I'll give you the pension or the payment for your newborn child.
I WANT TO MAKE A NOTE HERE ON THE STATEMENT OF UMAR(عُمَر)
هَلَّكِي فِيْ أَجَرْسَاقَهُ اللهَ إِلَيْكِ
"Would you like to accept a reward that Allahعَزّوجَلّ has sent to you".
Dear brothers and sisters sometimes, while you're walking down your path, going on with life
Allahعَزّوجَلّ would drop in front of you
just like that, it would just drop in front of you, an invitation to good,
you didn't ask for it, you didn't work to get it, it just drops in front of you.
And you are left with the option of accepting it or rejecting it.
It's an opportunity that Allahعَزّوجَلّ gives you and if you don't accept it,
it might be presented to you again.
But it's very likely that you will never ever have that chance again.
So, the choice is yours to accept it or not to accept it.
And these invitations to good come in different forms.
And it is a Taufeeq(توفيق) of Allahعَزّوجَلّ for you, it is a blessing,
if Allahعَزّوجَلّ presents you with such opportunity than you accept them.
And it's a wrath from Allah if you get all of these opportunities and you turned them down
because when Allahعَزّوجَلّ sends good to you, and you refuse it,
it's worse than not getting it at all.
With Firaun(فرعون) because Allahعَزّوجَلّ was sending him one sign after another
because he kept on turning them again and again,
his status was becoming lower and lower in the eyes of Allahعَزّوجَلّ
until, he reached to the rock bottom and Allahعَزّوجَلّ said about him and the likes of him.
وَإِنْ يَرَوْا كُلَّ آيَةٍ لَا يُؤْمِنُوا بِهَا
If they see every sign they're not going to believe in them.
Whatever sign you present them with,
it's not going to be sufficient to convince them that this is the truth.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ showed him seven Ayaat(آيات) Musa عليه السّلام was presenting them with miracles,
the stack and his hand that would be shining bright,
nothing was convincing to Firaun(فرعون).
وَجَحَدُوا بِهَا وَاسْتَيْقَنَتْهَا أَنْفُسُهُمْ
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ, says they rejected the truth when they had Yaqeen(يقين) in their hearts,
they were certain that this is the truth.
They had that certain faith that this the truth nevertheless, they rejected it publicly.
Brothers or sisters, Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ will present you with good opportunity.
See that's what life is about its opportunities,
you need to grab that opportunity as soon as you could lay your hands on it,
don't let it go.
Because some of those moments would never come again.
If you miss it once you missed it for life.
Sometimes For example, to give you an example,
somebody would come to you and present you with a project and ask for donation give for this project,
you become agitated these Muslims are asking for money all the time.
Someone is asking for a Masjid(مسجد), somebody is asking for an orphanage,
somebody is asking for widows you're asking for this and that
and you're just asking us and we're having this fundraising fatigue and you turned that offer down
and that particular project or opportunity could be one of those things that
most likely you're never going to hear again.
So, you turned that offer down, Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ sees that
and Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ holds back from you, some other good that was on its way,
why, because you're a person who doesn't deserve these opportunities.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ says;
وَمَنْ يُبَدِّلْ نِعْمَةَ اللَّهِ مِنْ بَعْدِ مَا جَاءَتْهُ فَإِنَّ اللَّهَ شَدِيدُ الْعِقَابِ۝
The one who changes the blessing of Allah after they received them,
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ is severe in punishment.
If Allah gives you a blessing and then you reject it and refuse it,
the punishment of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ is severe.
Now, the greatest blessing that Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has given you is that he has made you Muslim.
That's the greatest, you are Muslim.
Many people are taking that for granted and they are refusing this blessing that's Allah gave them.
So, Dawood(داؤد) becomes David and Muhammad(محمد) becomes mohd..,
They try to put on an external image that doesn't
imply in anyway shape or form that I'm a Muslim.
I don't want to be associated with those people, I want to show that I'm cool, like you.
Allah O Akbar(الله اكبر), you're turning down this offer that Allah gave you.
He hands you this application sign then ready that you are a member of the Ummah(امة) of Muhammadﷺ,
and you tear it and throw it in the bin,
just imagine what the status of such a person will be on the Day of Judgment.
And one of the worst things is to be ungrateful,
one of the worst things is when you are ungrateful for what Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has given you.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has blessed you, you need to thank Allah day and night
for the fact, that he has made you Muslim and one of the ways in which you thank Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ
is what Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has told Muhammadﷺ in Surah-tu-Duhaa(سورة ألضحى).
وَأَمَّا بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ فَحَدِّثْ۝
What the blessings of Allah on you, you need to speak about them.
You need to speak about the blessings of Allah on you,
You need to show the blessings of Allah on you.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ loves when he gives the person some blessing,
He loves for that person to present them.
Show off your Islam.
Be proud of it.
Talk about it.
Show that you're proud that Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has made you a member of the Ummah(امة) of Muhammad صلوات الله والسلام عليه.
And maybe when these opportunities of good land in your path maybe that's a sign that Allah loves you.
Wallah(والله) brothers, some people can talk about their experiences in that,
I don't have the time to go into it,
but Wallah(والله)  some brothers and sisters out of nowhere, Allah would just drop in front of them an opportunity of good
and they would grab it and it would change their lives,
it was either be an invitation to Islam, it would be an invitation to particular work
an offer would come to you and you don't know, where it came from
as if Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), it was miraculously destined to come to you
and you grab that opportunity and Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) it just changes your life.
It's a life changing event and it happens to many brothers
many people Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), the way they start practicing Islam is like that,
something just lands in their path and it changes their life.
I know a brother for example Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) he wouldn't even pray.
He was so away from Islam, not only was he not practicing Islam,
but he had something in his heart against Islam.
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), he lost a child
his first born child was diagnosed with this syndrome, so he passed away.
That event just changed his life 180 degrees.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) now, the brother is Aabid(عابد) worshipping Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
You never know what Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ is offering you except, when you accept it.
If you turn down that offer, you don't know what would have happened if you accepted it.
So, brothers don't waste these opportunities. Don't waste them.
Don't let them pass you by.
One of the Sahabah(صحابه), from At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف) he visited Makkah
in the early days of Da'wah(دعوة) as soon as Rasool Allah ﷺ started preaching Islam.
So, he saw a man come out of his tent and move in a strange way.
And then the man was followed by a woman.
And then the woman was followed by a young man and they all were doing the same movements.
And this man was a friend of Al-Abbas(العباس).
So, he asked Al-Abbas(العباس) what are these people doing, and who are they?
Al-Abbas(العباس) said that man, The first one is Muhammadﷺ, my nephew,
and he claims to be a prophet sent by Allah
and that woman is his wife,
and that young boy is Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب), and they are his followers.
The man said: I left, That's it!
I didn't do anything about it, I just left.
This man never became Muslim until At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف) was opened, probably 20 years later.
He would look back to that incident and he would say;
If I became a Muslim then, I would have been the fourth Muslim on the face of the earth.
Now, where am I.?
I'm way behind.
There are thousands of people before me.
I missed that golden opportunity.
Don't let these opportunities pass you by.
Especially in special times like this.
Brothers and sisters don't think that we are going through some mediocre times.
Don't think that this is a normal period in history.
We are going through some serious times.
You never know maybe the victory of the Ummah(امة) is around the bent.
Only Allah knows, we can't make a judgment.
But we are going through some special times.
It's a golden era.
Don't let this opportunity pass you by.
And as we said in the last session, you don't want to miss the train.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) walking with his with his servant.
He was so tired that evening, the servant Yarfaa(يرفع) said: So he went and just leaned on a wall and sat down,
exhausted and tired.
These patrols would take a toll on Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين),
he's been working for the entire day, going through these patrols at night.
he want to then make Tahajjud(تهجد), he was just exhausted.
He leaned on this wall and he just sat down.
This could be used as an example of some good that dropped in front of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
The particular wall that he kneeled on,
was the house of a mother and her daughter.
There was no man around, the mother wasn't married, and the girl wasn't married.
So Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) hears a conversation,
the mother, Allah Ho Alam(الله اعلم) divorced or widowed,
she told her daughter dilute the milk.
They used to dilute milk with water.
The daughter said: Didn't you know the orders of Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) Umar(عُمَر),
she said: What.?
The daughter said: Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) gave his instructions that milk should not be diluted.
He has banned the practice of diluting milk.
The mother said: My daughter Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) is not around
and he cannot hear us, go ahead and mix the milk with water,
just pour the water in there, nobody can see it.
What was the response of this young woman.
Allah Ho Akbar(الله اكبر) she said;
والله مَا كُنْتُ لِأُطِيَعَه’ فِي الْأَلَنْ وَأَعْصِيْهِ فِي الْخَلَا
I'm not going to be a person who would obey Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) in public and disobey him in private.
She refused the orders of her mother
because they conflicted with the orders of Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه ,
who is representing the law of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ on earth,
so obeying Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) is obeying Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ
and that take precedence over obeying your family, your parents.
لَا طَاعَةَ لِمَخْلُوْقٍ فِيْ مَعْصِيَةِالْخَالِقْ
You don't obey the creation, by disobeying the Creator.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told his servant mark this door and they left.
The next day early in the morning, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told his servant
go and check out the inhabitants of that house, I want to know who they are,
and tell me whether those women are married or not.
So he goes and he tells Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب)
that was a mother and her daughter there's no man in the house and they're not married.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) gathers his sons, he said: Oh my son's,
Is there anyone among you, who needs a wife?
And then he said: I don't feel like marrying any more
otherwise, I would have married that girl myself.
Abdullah Ibn Umar(عبدالله ابن عمر) said;
لي زوجه
I have a wife, am happy.
Abdur Rahman(عبدالرحمان) said, the same thing, Asim(عاصم) said;
لَا زَوْجَتَلِيْ وَزَوَّجْنِيْ
Oh my father, I have no wife, so please marry me.
He accepted the offer, this is another example of good dropping in your face and you accept it.
So Asim(عاصم) accepted the offer.
Obviously the girl was extremely happy to marry the son of a Ameer Ul-Mo'mineen(أميرالمؤمنين) Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه .
So, Asim(عاصم) marries this girl and they have a daughter.
Let me jump bit ahead in history.
In the Khilafah(خِلَافَه) of Bannu Ummayah(بنوأمية), there was one among them, who stood above all the rest.
Bannu Ummayah(بنوأمية) are the first royal family in Islam.
The last Khalifah(خليفه) is Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب), and the first king was Muawiyah(معاويه).
And he is the founder of the dynasty of Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية).
And this is probably the greatest Royal family that ever existed in our Islamic history,
but it was Kingdom they it's not a Khilafah(خِلَافَه),
it's not characterized as Khilafah(خِلَافَه) anymore, it's Kingdom.
The Khulafah(خلافاء) are four Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), Umar(عُمَر), Uthman(عثمان) and Ali(علي).
There was one among them, who stood above all the rest,
that some of our historians consider him to be the fifth Khalifah(خليفه)
and that's Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), he was different
he reminded everyone with the old good days of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) and they had the same name.
Umar bin Abdul Aziz رضي الله عنه and he only was a Khalifah(خليفه) for a little over two years.
But he caused a revolution in Islamic world
and by the way, our scholars have not came to a consensus on any Mujaddad(مجدد) except Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز),
He is the only one they agree that he is the Mujadded(مجدد), the reviver of the first century
because you know the Hadith(حديث), Rasool Allah ﷺ says: Allah send to this Ummah(امة)
someone, who would revive the religion every century.
They say that the Mujaddad(مجدد) of the first century which is the greatest century
was Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), and they all agree on that.
Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), one day he gathers Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية),
you know Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية), again royal family rich, wealthy they eat the best food
he gathers them he invites them over for a meal,
brings them in, he locks in up in his palace.
These are the seniors of Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية)
and he had them wait in there for hours
and they were so hungry they were saying where is the food.
Bring it!
Umar bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) said: Wait! Be patient! Be patient.
And they were waiting for hours, and they just couldn't wait anymore,
they said just bring us anything man, we want to eat,
he said: I'm preparing such a good meal for you.
They said: Listen we don't want to good meaI, just bring us something to eat we're hungry,
so he brought them swake(سويك),
swake(سويك) is considered to be the cheapest food,
it was the food of the masses not even that maybe even the masses don't have that anymore.
He brought them swake(سويك) and they ate it and they were very happy, they had so much of it.
Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) told them, did you like the meal, I see that you ate a lot
they said, well we were very hungry and that's all, what you gave us.
He said: Did that satisfy you, are you full?
They said: Yes we're full.
He said: If swake(سويك) can fill you up?
How come, you are becoming extravagant and wasting the money of the Ummah(امة) on those elaborate meals.
Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), he cut off those fat salaries that they were receiving.
He cut off all of the privileges that Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية) had.
I mean, he was just tightening the screws on them and they were getting fed up and frustrated,
so one of them gathered them and he said: Listen! Don't blame anyone but yourselves,
you bring a man from among you Bannu Ummayyah(بنوأمية)
and you marry him to a descendant of Umar(عُمَر)
and then the product of that marriage is a man
who looks like Bannu Ummayah(بنوأمية) from outside but he is Umar(عُمَر) from inside.
When Asim(عاصم) got married to that woman, Asim(عاصم) the son  of Umar(عُمَر)
got married to that woman who refused to dilute the milk.
They had a daughter,
that daughter was married to Abdul Aziz Bin Marwan(عبدالعزيزبن مروان),
one of the seniors and most noble of the family of Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية),
and he was the governor over Egypt
and Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) is their son.
So the mother of Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) is the grand daughter of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب).
And she is grand daughter of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) from the marriage of Asim(عاصم),
the son of Umar(عُمَر) and this righteous woman.
So she was surrounded with righteousness from both sides
and that righteousness was inherited to her son, Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز),
who turned out to be the revolution in the Muslim world,
who changed their lives within two years.
And all of that was caused by Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) leaning on a wall.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) you just take that one step towards Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ
you never know how many steps Allah will take towards you.
Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), the same name as Umar(عُمَر),
and Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) with Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), he didn't start out like that,
Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز), he was brought up in by two good Muslim parents.
I mean his father Abdul-Aziz Bin Marwan(عبدالعزيربن مروان) was a very righteous man, in his own right his mother obviously
but he was brought up within the environment of Bannu Umayyah(بنوأمية),
royal family, rich everybody respects you, you're wealthy, you eat the best food, you wear the best clothes.
Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) was so spoiled, they say people could walk down the street in Madina
and know that Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) pass through this road
because of the smell that he would leave behind, the perfume that he would leave behind.
And he used to wear the best clothes
but Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), when he became Khalifah(خليفه), his life turned upside down,
suddenly he had this fear of Allah in his heart and his wife would describe him.
His wife Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) Fatima Bint Abdul Malik(فاطمه بنت عبدالملك)
surrounded with Khulafah(خلفاء) from every direction.
The wife of Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز ), Fatima Bint Abdul Malik(فاطمه بنت عبدالملك)
her father was a Khalifah(خليفه) Abdul Malik Bin Marwan(عبدالملك بن مروان),
three of her brothers  Khulafah(خلفاء), Al Waleed Bin Abdul Malik(ألوليد بن عبدالملك),
Hisham Bin Abdul Malik(هشام بن عبدالملك) and Sulaiman Bin abdul Malik(سليمان بن عبدالملك)
and she got married to a Khalifah(خليفه).
She would say that my husband would sit on his bed and start weeping just weep, so much
I would put the blanket over him and then he would sleep
and then he would suddenly rise up in middle of the night and he would shake
like a bird would shake off water from his feathers
and I would ask him, why are you crying?
He would say because I remember the day will come,
when I will be told to either go to Paradise or go to hell fire.
There's gonna be a day, the day of judgment, when I will be handed my book
and I will be told to either go to Jannah(جنة) or go to Naar(النار).
There is no second chance and there's no way to reverse that command,
and he would just carry on crying.
That was the Taqwa(تقوى) and fear of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ
that Allah last put in the heart of Umar Bin Abdul Aziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز),
the Khalifah(خليفه) of the Muslims.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) his care would not only reach
the men and women and children of the Ummah(امة)
but he also would care for the animals that were living within his territory.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), he was seen beating up a camel shepherd, and he told him;
Why are you carrying on your camels a load that is too heavy for them?
Why are you breaking the back of your camels
and he was disciplining the owner because of that.
When Al-Akhnaf Bin Qais(اَلْاَحْنف بن قيس) and his people reached to Madina,
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) went with them to their campground
and he wasn't inspecting it and he took a glance at the camels and he told Al-Akhnaf(ألأخنف).
أَلَّا اتَّقَيْتُمُ اللهَ فِيْ رِكَائِبِكُمْ هَذِه؟
أَلَّاخَلَّيْتُمْ عَنْهَا فَأَكَلَتْ مِنْ نَبَتِ الْأرْضَ؟
Aren't you going to have Taqwa(تقوى) of Allah, when it comes to your animals!
Aren't you going to reduce the loads on them! Aren't you gonna allow them to eat.!
This was a delegation that is coming to Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), maybe to discuss
important matters regarding the political status of the Ummah(امة) and the military state
and Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) is talking about their camels.
One day Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) wanted to eat fresh fish,
they would get dry fish in Madina but he wanted fresh fish,
he felt like having some fresh fish.
He mentions that, to his servant, his servant travels to get him some.
It was a two day journey going, two the journey coming back.
He brought some fish for a Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) saw him when he came in, after two days travel.
The servant came off the camel and then started wiping the sweat of his camel,
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: I have tortured an animal to satisfy my desire,
Wallah "والله" I'm not gonna have anything of this to eat.
He said: I have tortured this camel it's sweating, it's tired, exhausted.
Why?
To satisfy my desire and he refused to have that fish.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), He was once seen inspecting a camel it was ill
so, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was, had his hand on the back of the camel
and he was looking at it and he said;
إِنِّيْ لَخَائِفٌ أَنْ أُسْأَلَ عَنْكَ يَوْمَ الْقِيَامَةْ
I'm afraid that I would be asked about you on the Day of Judgment.
So, the care of the Khalifah(خليفه) extended not only to the citizens of the Khilafah(خِلَافَه)
but also to the animals living there in.
Look at how we're living today, maybe it's better to be a camel
in the time of Umar(عُمَر) than to be a human today.
Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه  would encourage learning
and he had his approach to Islamic knowledge, we talked about how he did it during the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
He was very strict in a authenticity,
even though this was the early days and people were still honest
and trustworthy they weren't liars like now,
but they still wanted to make sure that the Ahadith(احاديث) that are narrative are authentic,
even though he is hearing them from Sahabah(صحابه) and Tab'een(تابعين),
one day Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري) who was a close friend of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
He called him,
you know Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) did not have a door to knock on, he had a curtain
so when you're seeking permission to meet him you just call his name,
Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري) called the first time, no response
second time, no response third time, no response, he left.
Later on, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) came out and he said,
I thought I heard, the calls of Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري)
They said: Yes! He was here but he left.
He said: Why did he leave?
They said: Because you are supposed to take permission three times,
if you don't hear back you leave, that's Sunnah(سنة),
you knock three times or call three times no response you leave.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Did he claimed that Rasool Allah ﷺ said that?
They said: Yes! He said: Bring him in,
they brought Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري),
He said: What did you say?
He said: Rasool Allah ﷺ said: You ask permission three times otherwise you leave,
he said: You're going to bring me a witness on that.
So he's not taking his word for it he said: You're going to bring me a witness for that,
Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري) went to Al-Ansaar(أنْصَار)
who were in a gathering and his face was pale.
They said: What happened?
He told them this story,
Obaiye Ibn Ka'ab(أبئي ابن كعب ) said: Let the youngest among us go with you.
Meaning that, this is common knowledge that everybody knows about it,
everyone in here knows about it.
Let the youngest among us go and give Shahadah(شهادة) about that, I mean everybody knows about it.
So Abu Saeed Al-Khudri(ابوسعيد الخدري) said: They appointed me to go, since I was youngest,
so I went to Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري) and I said;
Yes! That's what, I heard that Hadith(حديث) from Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Umar(عُمَر) said: You heard that, he said: Yes! I did.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: And I didn't know about it?
Yes! Because I was busy doing business in the market place.
And what kept me from hearing these Ahadith(احاديث) is trade "business".
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) blamed himself for not knowing this,
even though everybody else knew it.
But this is in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم) and also in a Al-Bukhari(البخاريْ).
But this shows you something that,
the Ahadith(احاديث) were not all known by all of the Sahabah(صحابه),
this Sahabi(صحابي) would know some Ahadith(احاديث), another Sahabi(صحابي) would know some Ahadith(احاديث).
So, their knowledge complements each other.
Number two, it shows you that the way of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was strict in the narration of Hadith(حديث).
He didn't want people narrating a Hadith(حديث) unless there's a confirmation,
there's a witness because you could forget, you can make a mistake,
you think that it was said, when it wasn't.
That's the nature of the human mind.
I mean Adam عليه السّلام, you know the story between him and Dawood(داؤد),
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Adam عليه السّلام was presented with his children, all of them.
Adam عليه السّلام saw all of his children
and they had light on them, according to their righteousness,
so he saw one of his children and he liked him, he said: Who is he?
They said: This is Nabi Ullah(نبي الله) Dawood(داؤد)!
Now all of these are his children.
So, they said, this is Nabi Ullah(نبي الله) Dawood(داؤد),
Adam عليه السّلام said: How long will Dawood(داؤد) live?
They said: He's gonna live 60 years.
Adam عليه السّلام said: Why don't you give him 40 years from my life.
So, that he would have hundred years to live.
So, they said: It's Maktoob(مكتبوب),
It's written that you are giving him 40 years of your life.
Tayyeb(طيب), when the angel of death came to Adam عليه السّلام claiming his Soul.
Adam عليه السّلام said: No! It's not my time yet, I still have 40 years in my life
because he was told that he's going to live for this time he gave 40 years to Dawood(داؤد).
So, the angel of death was 40 years early.
He said: No! I didn't say that.
I didn't give Dawood(داؤد) anything.
The angel said: Yes! You did.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
وَنُسِّيَ آدَمُ فَنُسِّيَتْ ذُرِّيَّتُهُ 'فَجَحَدَ آدَمُ ، فَجَحَدَتْ ذُرِّيَّتُهُ ، وَخَطِئَ آدَمُ فَخَطِئَتْ ذُرِّيَّتُهُ
And this Hadith(حديث) is Sahih(صحيح).
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:  Adam(آدم) Forgot, and that's why his children forget.
And Adam(آدم) refused and that's why his children of refuse.
He refused to accept the fact that he has actually, he did actually give Dawood 40 years of his life.
He refused to accept that.
Why? Because he forgot.
And that's the nature in us, we forget, you could forget.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was asking the Sahabah(صحابه): what should one do,
when the lose the major Taharah(طهارة) and there's no water around?
You know, it's not the Wadhoo(وضؤ) that you lost, you lost the major Taharah(طهارة).
Ammar Bin Yasir(عماربن ياسر) said: You, make Tayammum(تيمم).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Where did you get that from?
Ammar Bin Yasir(عماربن ياسر) Said: You forgot when me and you were traveling together?
And I lost my Taharah(طهارة).
And there was no water, so I rolled my body in the dirt like an animal would.
And then we went back to Rasool Allah ﷺ me and you, and we asked him about it.
He said: It was enough and sufficient for you to make Tayammum(تيمم).
Do you remember that? Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: No! I forgot about it.
This was a Hadith(حديث) that was mentioned in front of Umar(عُمَر) and he forgot about it.
Ammar Bin Yasir(عماربن ياسر) Said: Well, if you don't want me to mention this Hadith(حديث),
I won't mention it.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: No! Go ahead and mention it.
But after there was a witness to say that, this actually happened.
Therefore brothers, we learn from this, we should be careful in narrating Ahadith(احاديث)
and we should make sure that, the Ahadith(احاديث) that we're following are authentic,
you know, we don't want to be fooled by following Ahadith(احاديث) that Rasool Allah ﷺ did not say.
I mean, why should I do something, when Rasool Allah ﷺ did not tell me to do it
and I'm wasting my time doing something that is not expected from me.
I could use that time wisely by doing something that Allah wants me to do.
Don't think that you're a good Muslim by following everything you hear.
You need to make sure that the information that you're following is verified and true, he said;
تَفَكَّه’ قَبْلَ اَنْتَ سُوْدُوْفَتَمْنَعَكُمْ اَنَفَ مِنَّ التَّعَّلُّمْ فَتَعِيْشُوْجُهَالَه’
He said: Learn before you're put in positions of leadership
because then your pride will prevent you from learning.
So, you will live the rest of your life in a state of ignorance.
Learn when you're young, learn when you're young, don't wait.
because the older you become, the more senior you become,
the more you are seen in a high level and you are seen as a leader
and when you are seen as a leader,
you wouldn't go and sit under the knees of the scholars to learn,
and you wouldn't go around asking the people who are younger than you about knowledge
that's not the case with everyone many people are humbled throughout their life
and that's how we should be.
But that sometimes is a disease that could come to the heart,
and then Umar said: Then you will live the rest of your life in the state of ignorance.
Learn when you're young.
Plus learning when you're young is better for you
because that's when you have a stronger memory
and memory is very important when it comes to Islamic knowledge
because it depends on memorization. He also said:
يَهْدِيْمُ الْإِسْلَامَ ذَلَّةُ عَالِمٍ وَجَدَالُ مُنَافِقٍ بِالْقُرْآنِ وَ آئِمَّهْ مُزِّلُوْنْ
Islam will be destroyed by a mistake of a scholar,
by the arguments from Qur'an, by a Munafiq(منافق)
and by the misguided Imam(اِمَام)s.
Why do these destroy Islam because people follow their words,
a scholar who makes a mistake.
When Imam Ahmad Bin Humbal(إمام أحمد بن حنبل), was asked to say that Quran was created.
That was the Fitnah(فِتْنَه) that was the Bid'ah(بدعة) of Al-Moa Tazillah(معتزله).
They claim that Quran is not the word of Allah, but it's created.
But that was a very dangerous Bid'ah(بدعة).
Ahmad Bin Humbal رضي الله عنه stood firm and he refused to give in.
In his prison cell, one of the scholars came to him and said;
You are coerced to say that, you are being tortured.
So, you are allowed to speak out publicly, even if you don't believe in it.
Because you are under a state of coercion under duress.
So, you can say that it's created.
Ahmad Bin Humbal(أحمد بن حنبل) pulls the man and he opens the window
and he said: Do you see all of these people, the people of Baghdad(بغداد)? He said: Yes.
He said: If I say that, they will say it too.
People take my word, the people of Baghdad(بغداد) follow what I say.
Not just the people Baghdad(بغداد), but the people of the Muslim world.
If I say it, they will all accept it from me and I know that it's false but they won't,
so he refused to give in.
So, a mistake of a scholar can mislead an Ummah(امة) and
وجدال منافق بالقرآن
A Munafiq(منافق) who has knowledge of Quran
and he's arguing with you using Ayaat(آيات) of Qur'an, when he's a Munafiq(منافق),
that's very dangerous because he's using the evidence against you
and he's using Qur'an, so you accept that argument but he's twisting it.
He is playing around with it, He is playing around with the Ayaat(آيات) of Qur'an.
Munafiq Alaiem Bil Lisaaan(منافق عليهم بلسان) , A Munafiq(منافق) who has a  sweet tongue
and Aaemma Muzilloon(آئمَّه مُزلون), the Imam(اِمَام) is a leader,
Muzilloon(مُزلون) are the ones who deceive others,
so they are Imam(اِمَام)s who deceive the Ummah(امة).
And Imam(اِمَام) here could mean a political leader or a religious leader but maybe it's talking about political leaders
because the Ulema(علماء) are mentioned in the beginning of the statements,
so we would assume that Aimma(آئمه) here is talking about the political leaders,
who deceive others.
So, it's the Imam(اِمَام)s and the Ulema(علماء) who could deceive others
and they are also the ones who benefit the most,
so a person in that position could either benefit a lot or harm a lot.
IT SHUDDERS IN PAIN FREELY
MY CHASITY, MY MODESTY!
OH MUSLIM, YOU SAW
MY INJURY AND THE INJURY OF MY PRIDE